# Shyam Sundar J

sundarshyam842@gmail.com +91 6380463057 Tamil Nadu, India

"There's a first time for everything"! An enthusiastic student hoping to make myself known by building up new things. A Proficient Aeronautical Engineer with a strong base in Aerodynamics, Flight mechanics and an experience of 3 years in designing, fabricating and analyzing aircraft components and unmanned aerial vehicles.

**EDUCATION** 

Kumaraguru College of Technology, Coimbatore, (Anna University)

2020 - 2024 CGPA - 8.8 (Upto 7th semester)

Bachelor of Engineering, Aeronautical Engineering

#### **SOFTWARE SKILLS**

- Computational analysis Ansys (Intermediate) / OpenFOAM (Beginner)
- Programming languages C, C++, MATLAB (Intermediate)
- Design Tools Solid works (Beginner), CATIA.
- Post processors CFX post, ParaView (Beginner)

#### **FIELDS OF INTEREST**

• UAV design

- Aerodynamics
- Computational Fluid Dynamics

- Flight Mechanics
- Control Systems

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## 1) Kumaraguru College of Technology

Design of Unmanned airship to monitor environment of extra terrestrial planet

(Ongoing)

Study and design of Unmanned airship for environmental investigations on Proxima Centauri B for signs of possibilities for living by environmental sample collection

#### Numerical and computational investigations of Tilt Wing UAV for reducing power consumption (Ongoing)

Implementation of tilt wings with multi rotor controls for control surface less fixed wing maneuvering and implementation of convergent duct for potential thrust increment using catia, Ansys and controller design using MATLAB, Simulink.

#### 2) Aeromodelling Club of KCT

2021 - Current

### **Drone design Team**

#### Design and production of fixed wing plane

2023

Design, testing and fabrication of Fixed wing plane along with its component for efficient performance and High payload lifting capabilities using Catia and Ansys.

Participated in SAE drone development challenge and ranked 13 in all over India and 2nd in our region

CONFEDENCE BURLICATIONS
CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS
Design and Multi-Perspective Investigations on Aeroacoustic Noise Reduction Technologies for Anti-
Drone Propeller - ASME Gas Turbine India Conference 2023
(DOI - https://doi.org/10.1115/GTINDIA2023-117639)
JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS
Design, Control, Aerodynamic Performances, and Structural Integrity Investigations of Compact Ducted
Drone with Co-axial Propeller for High Altitude Surveillance - Scientific Reports, Springer Nature.
(DOI - https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-54174-x)
Multi perspective structural integrity based computational investigations on airframe of Gyrodyne-configured multi rotor UAV through coupled CFD and FEA approaches for various lightweight and sandwich composites and alloys - Reviews on Advanced Material Science and research (DOI - <a href="https://doi.org/10.1515/rams-2023-0147">https://doi.org/10.1515/rams-2023-0147</a> )
Design and multi-perspective investigations on the aerodynamic performance factors of conventional and advanced UAVs' micro gas turbine engine nozzle through validated CFD - International Journal of Fluid Mechanics Research, Begell house.  (DOI - <a href="https://doi.org/10.1615/InterJFluidMechRes.2024051464">https://doi.org/10.1615/InterJFluidMechRes.2024051464</a> )
Multi-Perspective Investigations of Aerosol's Nonlinear Impact on Unmanned Aerial Vehicle for Air
Pollution Control Applications under Various Aerosol Working Environments - Aerosol Science and
Engineering.
(DOI - https://doi.org/10.1007/s41810-024-00219-7)
PATENT PUBLICATION
Worked and contributed for 4 patent developments, in which 3 of them are under progress and 1 got published in Indian patents.
Tiltable main rotor with a servo motor for enhancing thrust and control in an elevated rotary wing UAV - Indian Patents. Published on January - 12, 2024. (Patent ID -202341089590)
CO CURRICULAR
Member of Aeromodelling Club of KCT     2021 - 2023

Co-Lead of UAV development team in Department of

Aeronautical Engineering

• Lead Coordinator of Research and Development in Department of Aeronautical Engineering

2021 - current

2021 - 2023

# 

• Zonal Table Tennis Tournament - Winner (3 years in a row)

2021 - 2023